<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-22T16:11:06+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Meg’s Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Video Game Escapism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/video/games/stress/2020/11/10/video-game-escapism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Video Game Escapism" /><published>2020-11-10T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-10T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/video/games/stress/2020/11/10/video-game-escapism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/video/games/stress/2020/11/10/video-game-escapism.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s 11:15 on a Tuesday and I am leaning towards my monitor, dragging my camera over the face of every visitor, occasionally pausing to read their thoughts, searching for criminal intentions à la Tom Cruise in Minority Report… There! The small pixelated lady at the hot dog stand has revealed that she is keen on theft! I hit the “eject” button, and watch with satisfaction as my equally pixelated security guard jogs over and evicts her from the premises. I’m sitting at the kitchen table playing Frontier Development’s Planet Zoo, I am on the hunt for pickpockets, and I am in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I uprooted my life and moved 5,000 miles away from my friends and family to live with my now-husband. Three months later, I was isolating in the countryside where my only social interaction (outside of my wonderful husband) was smiling at the people who used our cul-de-sac driveway to perform U-turns. I was on a temporary visa with no job, fretting constantly about catching COVID from the mailman, desperately missing my support network back home, and trying to fill eight hours a day while my husband worked. And that’s when I noticed that Planet Zoo was finally available on Steam for a reasonable price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From creating a magnificent entrance plaza to designing an aesthetically pleasing and stimulating habitat for your Bengal tiger, Planet Zoo is a delightful simulation game from Frontier Development that allows you to create and manage your very own zoo. In essence, you’re required to hire and oversee staff, ensure that your habitats meet each animal’s unique needs, and make certain that your guests have ample places to rest, eat, drink and purchase souvenirs. Frontier has guaranteed challenge by adding countless variables that affect all aspects of your zoo. Did you forget to place enough trash cans? Your guests’ happiness will plummet as they get litter stuck to their shoes. Didn’t check the temperature in your macaque habitat? Your monkeys will overheat and guests will begin to protest on behalf of their suffering. It is my ability to control these myriad variables that draws me to Planet Zoo and leads me to play it hour after hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am managing my zoo, I am able to easily identify and reduce or eliminate issues with a click of a button. Just as I enjoy searching for and ejecting pickpockets, I revel in the ability to determine what is causing my Baird’s Tapir so much stress and reduce it by simply placing a “Do Not Disturb” sign outside his habitat. I have total control over my zoo universe, and I feel capable of addressing any issue that flashes up on my notification screen. I often cannot rein in my anxiety-riddled ‘what-ifs’ about my own future, but at least I can help my bored grizzly bear by dropping him an extra enrichment item. I struggle to find the confidence needed to start building a new social circle, but I do feel great about my ability to design engaging scenery for my zoo guests. I may not be able to force people to actually wear their masks and stay 6 feet away from me, but I can hire and train an extra caretaker when my zoo trash cans start overflowing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not alone in my rampant video game escapism, especially in 2020. Between April and June of this year, overall total industry consumer spending on video gaming in the U.S. broke records with an astounding $11.6 billion, which NPD reports as a 30% increase from the same quarter of 2019. The same report revealed that overall video gaming hardware sales showed an increase of 57% percent! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npd.com/wps/portal/npd/us/news/press-releases/2020/the-npd-group-us-consumer-spend-on-video-game-products-continues-to-break-records/&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2020/05/12/video-game-industry-coronavirus/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/mattperez/2020/08/10/video-games-set-record-second-quarter-spurred-by-pandemic-sales/#249316186f4e&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; The jury is out, however, as to whether this increase in gaming during a chaotic time is good for our mental health or not. Pierre Taquet, a psych researcher from France, rather boldly stated that “playing video games excessively should be appealing to individuals with poor psychological functioning because games allow people to avoid their everyday problems”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01731/full&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; This is quite an extreme view in my opinion, but many studies have shown that too much gaming can have a detrimental effect on your physical health, social skills and attention span, to name a few. However, similar studies have found that video games can help strengthen your problem solving capabilities, your hand-eye coordination and spatial skills, your ability to manage resources and multitask, and even your perseverance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don’t really care if I am either expanding or diminishing my ability to concentrate during my many hours of Planet Zoo. Am I avoiding my everyday problems? Maybe. But when I’m creating a new primate exhibit or designing my latest block of toilets, I feel confident, competent, and most certainly in charge of my little microcosm. So, if you need me, you’ll find me hunched over my PC scanning for miniature thieves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="video" /><category term="games" /><category term="stress" /><summary type="html">It’s 11:15 on a Tuesday and I am leaning towards my monitor, dragging my camera over the face of every visitor, occasionally pausing to read their thoughts, searching for criminal intentions à la Tom Cruise in Minority Report… There! The small pixelated lady at the hot dog stand has revealed that she is keen on theft! I hit the “eject” button, and watch with satisfaction as my equally pixelated security guard jogs over and evicts her from the premises. I’m sitting at the kitchen table playing Frontier Development’s Planet Zoo, I am on the hunt for pickpockets, and I am in control.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Everyday Monster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/panic/stress/anxiety/2020/10/03/the-everyday-monster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Everyday Monster" /><published>2020-10-03T18:09:06+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-03T18:09:06+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/panic/stress/anxiety/2020/10/03/the-everyday-monster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/panic/stress/anxiety/2020/10/03/the-everyday-monster.html">&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to flip you like a penny, crumble you like a cracker and throw you away”, I recite for the fifteenth time as I pace another loop around the library, clutching my special hall pass signed by the school counselor. This secret mantra is drawn from &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;the children’s book&lt;/a&gt; The After-School Monster, which tells the tale of Luisa overcoming her fear and standing up to the big, hungry, horned beast who is hiding in her house when she arrives home from school. The monster chasing me around the empty halls of my middle school is my severe panic disorder and he is not just an after-school monster, or even just a during-school monster, he is an all-day everyday monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My everyday monster has been with me since I was 11 years old, and like Luisa’s monster, he was very large and very scary when he first arrived. Just as Luisa’s creature filled up her entire house, my panic disorder disrupted every aspect of my life, including the most basic human functions. He wouldn’t let me leave the house, and he wouldn’t let my mom leave me. He stood between me and my dad, and smothered my relationship with my brother. He crushed my lifelong love of school, and demolished my growing devotion to Tae Kwon Do. He said no to sleepovers, he said no to sleeping. He convinced me of many things- that I was seconds away from a stomach flu, that I was an open window away from being kidnapped, that I was simply going to die. He was strangling everything good and fun about being a kid, a daughter, being a sister, and a friend, and it seemed impossible that I’d be able to find Luisa’s courage to shrink him and stomp him right back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, though, my everyday monster fits in my pocket for the most part. I gave him a really good crushing when I returned to school and thrived. I heartily squashed him when I left home to attend college. We had a battle for the ages when I was learning to drive, but I eventually threw him right out the window. When one of my students vomited at my feet on the playground, he grew back his horns but I gave him a swift kick and helped my little Elle feel better. He sprouts sharp claws whenever I find myself wringing my hands at sunset, and his teeth sharpen any time that I have a stomach ache. And, lately, the global situation has been his favorite daily nourishment. I may never truly throw him away like Luisa’s rotten banana peel, nor will he always stay conveniently pocket-sized. But I am just as strong as Luisa, and I will keep finding the courage to flip my everyday monster like a penny, crumble him like a cracker, and do my best to throw him away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="panic" /><category term="stress" /><category term="anxiety" /><summary type="html">“I’m going to flip you like a penny, crumble you like a cracker and throw you away”, I recite for the fifteenth time as I pace another loop around the library, clutching my special hall pass signed by the school counselor. This secret mantra is drawn from the children’s book The After-School Monster, which tells the tale of Luisa overcoming her fear and standing up to the big, hungry, horned beast who is hiding in her house when she arrives home from school. The monster chasing me around the empty halls of my middle school is my severe panic disorder and he is not just an after-school monster, or even just a during-school monster, he is an all-day everyday monster.</summary></entry></feed>